[man on radio] The forecast,
sunshine through today
with seasonal temperatures.
We should return--
[up-tempo instrumental music playing]
[Jerry]
This is a 1958 Cadillac Eldorado Seville
in Gleneagles green,
with a Bimini green metallic interior
covered in protective plastic.
It has a 335 horsepower V8 engine.
It goes 0 to 60 in 10.7 seconds,
but who cares?
The longer people are looking
at you in this car, the better.
If you were an American at the top
of whatever you did in the late '50s
and you wanted to drive around
in a mobile version of Las Vegas,
this is it.
A car that's as thrilled with itself
as you are.
[phone ringing]
-[Don] Hello?
-[Jerry] Don? It's Jerry.
[Don] I'm so excited, I'm going
to drop my pants and fire a rocket.
What's the matter, you need money?
What can I do for you?
[Jerry] I'm looking forward
to seeing you today.
[Don] You're like a schnorrer
with this car crap.
It's doing a lot to me, you know that.
-[Jerry] Oh, yeah?
-[Don] How about nothing?
I'm Jerry Seinfeld,
and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
That's funny.
[Jerry] My special guest today
is one of the faces that, in my opinion,
would be on the Mount Rushmore
of stand-up comedy...
Mr. Don Rickles.
The other three are Pryor,
Carlin, and Cosby, by the way.
I've known Don for over 20 years,
and as far as I'm concerned,
he is the man.
-[Don] Hello?
-[Jerry] Don?
[Don] What do you mean, "Don"?
This isn't a grocery store
for Christ's sake, "Don." [chuckles]
-[Jerry] Mr. Rickles?
-[Don] Listen, hurry up,
'cause for the money you're paying me,
this should be over.
Kiss the mezuzah.
-Okay. You don't believe in that? Figures.
-No...
You're one of those voodoo Jews. Okay.
[lively piano music playing]
-[Don] You're driving?
-[Jerry] Yes.
[Jerry] I'm gonna drive,
you're gonna jog alongside.
Is that all right?
Do you have to wear the hat?
-You don't like the hat?
-I wanna see your face.
I paid for Don Rickles.
Take me back to 1958.
Could you afford a car like this in 1958?
No, no. Bicycle.
In those days, my mother, rest her soul,
she had her friend drive me to jobs
and they used to sit in the kitchen
and wait for the boss to come out,
and say,
"We don't want this man here,
he's ruining our business."
My best recollection is
I went to the American Academy
of Dramatic Arts.
-Right. That's not comedy.
-Yeah, I know.
-This is a show about comedy.
-Yeah. Really?
[both chuckling]
Who were your friends,
who did you pal around with?
-Guy called Herkie Styles.
-Herkie Styles.
-That's a good name for a comic.
-He was a wonderful comedian.
-I wasn't much of a hang-around guy...
-Right.
...in the horse room or something.
I never did that.
The where? The horse room?
-You know, in Vegas.
-You mean betting.
-Betting, yeah.
-So, you didn't gamble.
-Were you a drinker?
-In those days, I drank
from the side of the mouth,
little drippings of vodka.
When you worked those places,
you had to have guts.
-Yes.
-[chuckles]
And a Diet Coke wouldn't do it, you know.
As time marched on,
I never have a drink when I'm not working.
-Never.
-Really?
Except socially, in a restaurant.
At home, never drink.
Then it's not never. You do.
Well, what are you,
from Alcoholics Anonymous?
-I'm trying to find out--
-You're trying to put me in my place.
-I wanna figure out what happened.
-I don't like that.
The wife has been trying for a long time.
She keeps moving the medicine.
I get up in the morning and say,
"Where's my pills?"
She says, "Find them. Find them."
She made it a scavenger hunt
to stay alive, for crying out loud.
[both laughing]
-[Don] And you know who else I love?
-De Niro.
I worked with him in Casino.
You know what I did? The opening line,
I said... God's truth, Jerry,
with the lights and Scorsese
and everything.
And they go, "Roll them!"
And he goes, [mumbling] "You know...
Charlie... [mumbles] "
I said, "Hold it, I can't work
with this man.
"The man's mumbling and spitting up
all over, I don't need this, Marty."
The crew was on the floor.
They said, "Don't say nothing.
Bob don't like that we get it."
The second day, we were having vodka
in the dressing room every night.
"To Italy." Boom.
[Jerry] But you never have a drink.
I worked for four presidents
of the United States.
Wow. I know the Reagan one.
That was a big night, wasn't it?
That was one of the most exciting nights,
I think, of my career.
Sinatra said, "If you don't have
Sir Rickles, you don't have me."
-That's what he said.
-Really?
And Ronald Reagan liked me
'cause when he was governor,
I used to rib him.
I said, "My cousin's going
to the chair Thursday.
One phone call, one call.
Ronnie, you have nothing else to do.
Forget the golf game,
all you have to say is,
'Warden, he's innocent.'"
And he'd fall out of the chair.
[Jerry laughing]
And the big line
was the Billy Graham thing.
"Dr. Graham, if you could fix this hand.
It's making me crazy."
You have to be so much funnier
than most guys to do what you do.
There's no act, no, "You should hear
what Don says about this or that."
You're just using your raw funny
all the time.
-Thank you.
-Which is very difficult to do.
Any comedian knows that.
What was it like playing the Copacabana?
I was handled by a fellow called
Joe Scandore for about 40 years.
-I remember Joe.
-He knew a lot of guys,
-their noses were crooked, you know?
-Yes, I do.
And in those days,
I always got a chance in a nightclub.
They found me funny,
that's how I got to the Copa.
[Don] Everybody that was important came.
Really.
Jules Podell said,
[mimicking Jules] "I don't want this man
in my place. I don't need no wise guy,
no dummy that makes fun of my people.
This is high-class, it's the Copacabana,
and this kid will never,
as long as I'm alive, star in this place."
And Joe had a high voice, just like,
[high-pitched] "Why? He's a good comedian,
don't you understand?"
[mimicking Jules] "I don't care, Joe,
he's not gonna be in this place."
Two days later,
[mimicking Jules] "Hello, Don,
you're one of the cleverest,
most entertaining guys
and you will star at the Copacabana."
Have you eaten yet today? Anything?
-I had my cornflakes.
-Cornflakes, you had?
-Yeah.
-You really are living in 1958.
-[Don] Yeah.
-What about coffee?
-Yeah.
-But are you in the mood for coffee?
Yeah, what is "in the mood"?
It's America, of course I'll have coffee.
[Jerry] All right,
let's go get some coffee.
-[waiter] Coffee?
-Two coffees, please. Thank you so much.
And Sweet'n Low.
Sweet'n Low.
You don't wanna get heavy?
Eighty-seven in May.
Eighty-seven, God bless you.
You know, I keep working.
I gotta keep working.
When I was in the Philippines,
the joke was...
I come out of high school,
"You'll fail..."
President of everything
and failing every subject.
So my father, rest his soul, said,
"You're going to Grand Central.
Enlist.
You gotta get outa high school."
And first thing they do,
they take my blood pressure.
You know, 'cause I was a very hyper guy.
A nervous wreck, like I am today.
Okay, look.
[mimicking blood pressure cuff hissing]
-[Jerry laughing]
-"You feelin' all right?"
[laughing]
I said, "Yeah, Doc, what's wrong?"
"Oh. Nothing."
-"Let me try to hear."
-[laughing]
I did about four...
[mimicking cuff hissing] You know?
-He said, "Okay."
-[pounding]
I said, "What does that mean?"
"Means you're in the Navy now, son."
I said, "I applied for special service.
I do comedy and jokes."
"Comedy and jokes."
"And where would you like
to be stationed?"
"San Diego, sir. I mean,
there's a great atmosphere to do a show."
"San Diego... Do a show."
Next thing you know, I'm on a ship.
I said, "Where we going?"
"The Philippines."
So you would do shows in the Navy?
Yeah, we had shows on the ship.
At night, they'd put up a platform.
They said, "Rickles is on." You know.
But my joke worked all the time.
"I do comedy."
[chuckling]
One guy always kept saying,
"Just keep firing." That's my big joke.
"Keep firing,
don't worry about the comedy.
-We'll talk about that later."
-[both laughing]
And I was on the 20 mm gun.
[mimicking gunshots]
When the smoke cleared, they lift
the canister, put it on the ground.
"Lieutenant, I know... See, I do comedy."
[laughing] I was such a schmuck.
[chuckles] I still thought
that maybe they'd transfer me.
-In the middle of shit...
-To San Diego.
Yeah, in the middle of...
[mimicking gunshots]
Bob Newhart and I. Isn't that something?
-Two guys that are completely different.
-Right.
He came from the Midwest.
A real giant gentile, God bless him.
And it's the wives.
I say this on the show.
The wives. You know that with your wife.
If your wife likes the woman
that you're...
And you like the guy,
and she don't like the guy...
-It's over. It's over, am I right?
-That's it.
And I said, "This guy's great, Barbara."
[mimicking Barbara]
"You're not gonna see him."
[both laughing]
Like in Europe,
we used to go into Harrods.
And she'd buy... "I'll get these gloves.
And listen, I'll have that skirt.
Oh, yeah, and that jacket.
Oh, yes, and give me that scarf."
And I'd say,
"Oh, boy, this is a beautiful tie."
"You don't need that."
[both laughing]
That was my name. "You don't need that."
-I know you're a baseball guy.
-Dodgers. I used to go down in the dugout.
Talked to Lasorda.
Put on the uniform one night.
He said, "Go out and take
the pitcher out." I'm in the uniform.
Walk out to the mound. 50,000 people.
"Give me the ball."
[high-pitched] "You don't know me.
What are you doing here?"
Harry Wendelstedt, who passed away,
he was the head umpire, comes racing out.
Rips off the mask, "What the hell...
-Don, can you get me four seats in Vegas,
-[slapping table]
the Dean Martin show?
Four, just four seats."
-Can I get you anything over here?
-How about a picture of China?
[laughing]
-I'll go with you.
-Sarah.
[Sarah] Yes?
-We'll get together, don't say nothing.
-I won't.
Because as soon as I saw you,
I knew. I knew it was you and me.
In those days, it was unheard of
to do what I did.
-Right.
-It was, "Ugh, what is he doing?"
At the beginning, in the audiences,
there was one guy, a wise guy in Montreal,
and he was a bad guy, really bad.
And he was sitting ringside,
and I look at the wife.
I said, "Sir, is that your wife?"
Guy, "Yeah." I said...
"Ooh."
-[both chuckling]
-Isn't that something?
Jerry, I said...
"She's a moose."
[both laughing]
Then I turned to the band.
"Am I crazy? You guys take a look."
They all stand up and go,
"Ooh."
[laughing]
-Enjoy your dinner.
-Thanks.
Now I'm gonna watch an old Jew
eat a salad.
-Yeah.
I was the only guy with Frank Sinatra
to get away with murder.
Rest his soul, I loved him.
-Were you guys really friends?
-No.
We're sitting here now, right?
And he would say, "You know..."
I'd say, "Frank, I'm talking."
-Nobody else would do that.
-Nobody.
-And he would go...
-[slams table]
-He loved it.
-Oh, loved it.
Give me a night in Vegas,
you're working, he's working...
After the show, you get together?
-Yeah.
-Take me through that.
Usually, I'd have to chase the car.
"Wait up, Frank."
[chuckling]
Whatever he said, we loved.
It was exciting to be with him
-and do what he wanted.
-Why?
He had a charisma that was...
You walked into a restaurant, it stopped.
-It stopped, I'm telling you.
-Right.
But after the shows,
we usually went someplace,
sit with him till 5:00,
6:00 in the morning.
-With drinks. Yeah.
-5:00, 6:00 in the morning?
Then we used to go early in the morning
out to Lake Mead.
I learned how to water-ski.
I got pictures of me on one ski, two skis.
-After staying up all night?
-Yeah.
-Go water-skiing?
-Go water-skiing.
-We're sitting in a hotel...
-Yeah.
...in Monte Carlo, big bay window,
sitting there.
Frank, Tony, myself.
So...
lightning. [mimicking thunderclap]
Frank says, "Don...
You and Julie,
why don't you go outside...
and tell that cameraman...
that photographer,
we're gonna knock him on his ass
-if he keeps taking pictures."
-Right.
Pouring rain and lightning.
It was lightning.
[mimicking thunderclap]
I said, "Well, Frank--"
"Don't out-frank me.
Just go out there now and stop him.
-Put a stop. I want it now."
-Right.
Near the door, I was in the rain
and tuxedo going,
"And don't you start, and you put..."
Talking to nobody.
"And you stop that lightning,
understand me?"
Thank God, the rain stopped.
And we came back in soaking wet
and sat down. He said,
"Thanks guys. You did a good job."
[laughing]
True story.
But I know that if I had more education,
I could've been a damn good psychiatrist.
Really. That's what I do on the stage,
it's a form of psychiatry.
I know, but what fun is that?
Telling people--
-Well, I didn't do it.
-[both chuckle]
I take it as a credit that I possibly
could have... in my own mind.
Well, if you need delusions,
that's your business.
[Jerry] So, when you first started out
in the lounges in Vegas,
-what time was your last show?
-12:00, 2:00, and 5:00 in the morning.
-Three shows a night?
-Three a night.
Over a bar, with guys like this...
"Eddie, what is this...
What, is this guy funny?"
It was tough.
-Tough. Huh, jeez.
-Till 5:00?
"Sir...
When you get a minute, could you look up?"
I'm on stage, right?
And it's packed, the lounge.
And the casino's packed,
and it's noisy, no way to stop the noise.
And I'd run out into the casino,
and get on a crap table, and yell,
"All right, that's it!
I'm on a goddamn stage and this noise
gotta stop, you understand me?"
I swear, on my father's grave...
["La Virgen de la Macarena" playing]
Who came up with the bullfighter theme
on The Tonight Show
as a play on for you?
-Me. Yeah.
-You did?
Accidentally.
-[cheering, applauding]
-["La Virgen de la Macarena" continues]
-It's me, that's what I do.
-Right.
That's why, when I'd go on a show...
Bob Hope in those days, with the cards...
Mm-hmm.
In the middle of a scene
with George Foreman,
I'd get off the card and say, "George,
stand in the corner, knock yourself out."
Now they couldn't write that.
And the way I say it,
that's not a hilarious thing.
But when I say it, they scream,
because of the way I say it.
-You grew up in New York, right?
-Yes.
Do you have relatives still around?
My mother.
-Your mother's still with us?
-Yeah, 99 this year.
-Oh, my God!
-[pounding]
What am I complaining about? Jesus.
-That's what I'm trying to figure out.
-[laughing]
[Jerry] Nobody wants Don Rickles
for a shrink, by the way.
I'm counting on you, anything we said
that might make somebody look bad,
-I'll kill you.
-I would never do that.
-[Jerry] You think I'm stupid?
-[Don] Yeah.
[both laughing]
...used to do all table stuff.
-You ever hear that name?
-Yeah.
And he would take farina,
put it in his mouth and say,
"Miss, could I have that... [mumbles]"
And he'd let it fall all over the table.
And he was funny as hell.
You got hysterical.
And then, when he went on the stage,
right in the toilet.
He had four, five jokes, and that was it.
But we'd sit in the Cabana,
in the daytime. See, like you,
-pounding the beach chairs on the floor.
-The guy is like that.
-On the floor.
-I know. I know.
We went to the place.
They get up in front of the crowd,
nothing.
Dead. Dead.
-Why is that, Don?
-Ah, who knows? Who knows, you know?
Let me take care of this.
No, I insist.
-You see how I was fighting over it?
-[laughing]